<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>External Resources on OTS-DS</title>
    <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in External Resources on OTS-DS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 03:00:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn R</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/learn_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:47:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/learn_r/</guid>
      <description>Swirl: Swirl is an R package that allows you to learn R interactively in the R console.
 Introduction to R from DataCamp: A solid, 6-part intro to the basics of the R language with 4-5 hours of material. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in continuing with DataCamp you can purchase a subscription for 22€ per month, which gives you access to 137 courses (R and Python) and a number of career and skill tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Python</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/learn_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:47:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/learn_python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Programming with Python from OTS: Perfect for anyone with limited exposure to programming. Covers everything you need to get started with Python. Available in English, German, Spanish, Russian, Korean, and Romanian.
 Automate the Boring Stuff with Python: Teaches Python as a means to get things done. Free if you use the website, also available as a book and a Udemy course.
 Python Course: Probably one of the most comprehensive free tutorials available, it covers everything from &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; to advanced OOP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/math_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 03:00:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/math_stats/</guid>
      <description>Statistics with R Specialization: A popular, semester-long statistics course from from Duke University &amp;amp; Coursera. Focus is on stats with programming assignments in R. That said, it is possible to make it through the course without knowing much about R. Topics: inference, correlation, regression, Bayesian statistics.
 Computational Linear Algebra for Coders: From the good people at fast.ai.
 Linear Algebra - Foundations to Frontiers: A popular, semester-long course from the University of Texas at Austin and edX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 03:00:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>Tutorials, R and Python  Intro to Machine Learning (Py): An excellent introduction to applied ML from Udacity. The course focuses on the ML library scikit-learn. Part of Udacity&amp;rsquo;s Data Analyst Nanodegree, it takes an estimated 10 weeks to complete.
 Machine Learning (Py): A popular introduction to the theory behind common ML algorithms, from Coursera founder and Stanford professor Andrew Ng. It takes an estimated 11 weeks to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:47:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/datasets/</guid>
      <description>UCI Machine Learning Repository: More than 400 ML datasets.
 Kaggle: More than 8,000 datasets of varying quality covering numerous topics.
 Rdatasets: A collection of 1161 datasets that were originally distributed alongside the statistical software environment R and some of its add-on packages. Curated by Vincent Arel-Bundock.
 Awesome Public Datasets: A VERY large list of tidied, public data sets. Most of the datasets are free, some are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitions</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/competitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:50:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/competitions/</guid>
      <description> DrivenData: Data science competitions geared towards social causes, including health, education, and development.
 Kaggle: A popular data science competition platform.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:47:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/people/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Rachael Tatman (R/Py): Data Scientist @kaggle &amp;amp; Linguistics PhD. Data science, stats, R, Python, NLP and linguistics. Live coding data science on twitch and other interactive projects.
 Mara Averick (R): tidyverse dev advocate @rstudio #rstats, #datanerd, #civictech 💖er, 🏀 stats junkie, using #data4good (&amp;amp;or 🥇 fantasy sports), lesser ½ of @batpigandme 🦇🐽
 Julia Silge (R): Data science and visualization at @StackOverflow, #rstats, author of Text Mining with R, parenthood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 02:55:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opentechschool.github.io/datascience/external_resources/news/</guid>
      <description>Analytics Vidhya: A comprehensive data science website providing resources for pretty much everything related to data science/analysis. Their ambitious blurb: Learn everything about analytics.
 KDnuggets: A website covering everything DS and ML related.
 Data Machina: A weekly digest of data science curiosities, machine intelligence, data geekery, and other amenities.
 Revolution Analytics (R): Daily news about using open source R for big data analysis, predictive modeling, data science, and visualization since 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>